The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal\NSubtitles by Bonobosubs\Nhttps://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Why are you trying to hurt innocents ?
It looks like the Heng Yue Sect also has talented people.
I'll tell you
if you can beat me !
It’s Senior Brother’s Eagle Claw !
He'll win for sure !
Die !
A mere 6th layer of Qi Condensation dares to try to hurt me !?
You just wait until I chop off your limbs
and make you regret being born in this trash Heng Yue Sect !
Brat...
You brought this upon yourself !
Go !
Explode !
Who is this Senior Brother ?
I have no idea...
It looks like he's a regular disciple.
He...
he is Wang Lin !
He's that trash who only got accepted because
Xu Fei\NHeng Yue Sect disciple\N3rd layer of Qi Condensation
he tried to kill himself.
Weird...
Why does it look like no one knows that disciple ?
You’re only at the 6th layer of Qi Condensation !
It should be impossible for you to kill my Black Python !
14th layer of Qi Condensation ?
How can this be ?
I surrender ! I surrender !
Stop...
Stop !
When you were about to hurt innocents earlier,
would you have stopped ?!
You’re courting death !
You dare to try to kill in Heng Yue ?
Do you think the Heng Yue Sect is that weak ?
Liu Wenju\NHeng Yue Sect Ancestor\NMiddle stage Core Formation
Greetings Ancestor.
Is your name Wang Lin ?
From now on,
you are a core sect disciple.
Thank you Ancestor !
This competition was won by
the Heng Yue Sect !
Amazing ! Junior Brother, you’re incredible !
How did you cultivate to peak Qi Condensation ?
Yeah, how did you do it ?
This fellow cultivator really is good natured.
Little sister, let’s go.
The Xuan Dao Sect won't let this slide,
the Heng Yue Sect is in trouble.
We won’t see you off.
We’ll meet again.
The Sect Competition has concluded.
The mortals attending will be escorted out by disciples.
Father !
Mother !
I didn't fail to live up to your expectations !
The Ancestor said he’ll take me as a white-robed disciple !
In the future, your son will...
Mother...
What’s wrong ?
My son...
You’ve lost weight....
Mother...
Dear,
didn’t we bring something for Tie Zhu ?
I almost forgot...
Take this, and this,
and this spiced beef, take all of it !
Okay.
Mother...
You must also take care of yourself.
This bead contains my Divine Sense.
If you’re ever in danger,
you just need to crush it
and I’ll come immediately.
Okay, okay, your father will remember.
Let's go.
Juniors of the Heng Yue Sect,
leave Heng Yue Mountain right now !
Senior Piao Nanzi,
our sects have always been on good terms.
My master still hasn't returned...
Hasn’t returned ?
Piao Nanzi\NXuan Dao Sect Ancestor\NMiddle stage Nascent Soul
I thought Junior Ouyang told you a few days ago.
Your master...
and all the Nascent Soul Ancestors of the Heng Yue Sect
died on the Foreign Battlefield.
Master...
And now, this old man has come to claim Heng Yue Mountain !
Everyone, stand your ground !
The Heng Yue Sect has been around for a thousand years.
It won't fall by your hands !
All of the Elders
will help me to activate the Sect Protection Formation !
Huanglong,
take the disciples down the mountain.
All the disciples, follow me !
Hurry up !
Sect Protection Formation,
activate !
All of the Heng Yue Sect disciples
must leave the mountain !
It's just a mere Nascent Soul cultivator...
He's just an ant I would've crushed in the past.
Disciple,
come with me.
Master...
If you gently open the formation,
everything will go well.
Wait for me to pack my things,
and we’ll leave together.
Leave ?
The Elders and Ancestors are operating the formation.
Why isn't Master going ?
They can't protect the sect.
Before a Nascent Soul cultivator, it's useless.
This Foundation Stabilizing Tea
will lose its effect if we don't drink it now.
We can't take it with us
so we might as well drink it.
Even I don't often drink this herb.
My disciple,
have some.
There's a lot of it,
why aren't you also drinking ?
Why aren't you listening to your Master ?
This is a rare tea,
drink it now !
But if I drink it,
it will silently poison me again, right ?
Just like that pill...
What did you put inside ?
Qi Scattering Grass
or Three Threadworm Grass ?
Since you already know,
don’t blame me for being ruthless !
A binding formation !?
You insisted on doing this the hard way !
If this formation was operated by a Nascent Soul,
it would be truly formidable.
It's a pity...
Go !
Do you think this old man is afraid of your formation ?!
Zhang Kuang, Lu Song,
leave with the rest of the disciples !
Yes !
Break !
Ancestor, focus on the formation.
Leave the rest to me.
Huanglong, what are you doing ?!
Protecting the Heng Yue Sect
is also the duty of the Sect Leader !
Are you burning your lifespan ?
Huanglong, stop this madness !
Piao Nanzi ! As long as I, Huanglong, am here,
even if my soul scatters,
you won't set a foot in the Heng Yue Sect !
Unaware of your limits ?
Huanglong !
Sect Leader ! Senior Brother !
This Huanglong brat
was nothing special.
The Heng Yue Sect raised me for 20 years.
Today, I will protect the Heng Yue Sect !
Today, we protect the Heng Yue Sect !
Piao Nanzi, as long as one Heng Yue disciple remains,
you won’t take Heng Yue Mountain !
Nonsense !
Break !
Don’t waste your energy.
You can't break this formation
with your cultivation.
Where is that pill I gave you ?
It was supposed to slow down your cultivation
so I could control you.
Then, you’d willingly hand over your treasures.
But you somehow cured the poison
and increased your cultivation this much ?
This saves me some trouble !
I advise you not to resist
or you won't even keep your consciousness.
Wang Lin !
Wang Lin, wake up !
Wake up, Wang Lin !
Wang Lin !
Wake up !
What is this artifact !?
Where...
Where did you hide it !?
What’s happening !?
Why am I not able to move anymore !?
Sun Dazhu...
release the formation.
Three Threadworm Grass...
When did you poison me ?!
When I understood you were the one behind Senior Brother Liu.
Three Threadworm Grass,
it's essential for refining puppets.
It can also be used as a poison to control someone temporarily.
It's a good plant.
Just in case,
I made tea poisoned with the Three Threadworm Grass
and made you drink it.
If you didn't do anything,
I wouldn't have used it.
But since you did,
I have no issues with using your own methods
against you !
My disciple, let's talk this out !
Let's talk, I beg you !
You're decisive when you kill,
brave and cunning.
This is how a cultivator should be !
You can’t defend Heng Yue Mountain.
Instead of letting others claim it,
give it to my Xuan Dao Sect.
Alright...
Heng Yue Sect disciples,
we're leaving, follow me.
The Xuan Dao Sect is taking new disciples in !
Those who stay will receive healing pills and cultivation pills.
Thank you, Ancestor !
I... I’ll stay !
I will stay too !
Me too,
I’ll join the Xuan Dao Sect !
You ungrateful people !
Everyone has their own ambitions; there's no need to force them.
A renowned sect
can be destroyed in a single day.
Is this the cruelty of the cultivation world ?
Senior,
teach me Foundation Establishment.
I must get stronger
in order to control my own fate.
Well said !
You finally figured it out, kid.
4 years later
Mountains near\NHeng Yue Mountain
Both Wang Zhuo and I come from the Heng Yue Sect.
I didn't expect that in just 4 years
he would already be training in the back mountain
with the core disciples of the Xuan Dao Sect.
Don’t worry.
Once we capture an Ink Crystal Beast to use as a Sword Spirit,
you’ll get to train there too.
Third Senior Brother,
can we really catch one here ?
Chang Hao\NXuan Dao Sect disciple\N6th layer of Qi Condensation
This place became rich in spiritual energy 2 years ago
so it attracted many Spirit Beasts.
Xu Fei\NXuan Dao Sect disciple\N6th layer of Qi Condensation
Maybe there are some treasures here ?
This is...
Such a powerful aura !
Junior Chang Hao of the Xuan Dao Sect,
didn't know Senior was cultivating here.
Please forgive me
for my rudeness.
Leave at once !
Let’s go !
Wang Lin\N15th layer of Qi Condensation
The Divine Sense is a part of counsciousness split off from the cultivator's soul. It can be used to scan things or people (this is how cultivators check each other's cultivation level), to control artifacts (magic objects) or just to attack someone else directly. The Divine Sense can be spread out over an area with low precision or it can be focused on a specific point for more accuracy.\N\NSect Leader Huanglong burned his lifespan to become stronger in the fight. What does it mean ? Aren't Immortals immortal ?\NNo, they aren't immortal. The lifespan of a cultivator is a ressource that is finite and can be used in desperate situations (most cultivators keep their lifespan to live through it though). Lifespan is increased upon a breakthrough or consuming certain medecines (pills). You can think of cultivation as a game of cat and mouse between the cultivators (that cultivate and increase their lifespan) and the law of the heavens (that is coming after them if they run out of lifespan).\N\NPills are quite self-explanatory, they are medecines made from ingredients rich in spiritual energy and can have many different types of properties and usages. Pill-making is a form of external alchemy which is opposed to internal alchemy (cultivation).\N\NThe yellow paper Sun Dazhu was using to make a formation is called a talisman. Talismans have effects in function of what symbol is drawn on them, for example a speed talisman can be put on your legs in order to run faster. Talismans are pretty weak and overall only used by low level cultivators.
I've been walking this path for endless years
just to catch a glimpse of your silhouette.
Is it the compass of fate
that wrote this outcome for us ?
The heavens want to erase your existence,
that's the obsession guiding me.
Is this the path to uncover
truths from falsehoods ?
In a world of murk and shadow,
only the flame of truth can light the way.
Look at them all,
being carried by the waves.
being drowned.
I don't want to believe in whoever decides fate,
I will let the world refine my soul.
So what if I become an Immortal and defy the heavens ?
I will fight.
I'll break through the abyss of despair
to finally learn who I really am.
My body is stained by the bloody color of slaughter,
I embrace this obsession.
I won't glance back at the wasteland I left behind.
Even if this suffering shatters my soul
and I'm reborn countless times in hell,
I'll still fight.
It's hard to avoid loneliness
when you are above everyone else.
Can a moth that has witnessed the flames of a Suzaku
be afraid of a firefly ?